<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Matthew C Dev</title>
    <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Matthew C Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 13:15:45 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matthewc.dev/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finding The Best Homemade Vegan Ice Cream</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vegan-ice-cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 13:15:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vegan-ice-cream/</guid>
      <description>Since I hate sites that make you read a whole story to get the recipes, out of the five different ice creams, here were the two highest ranking ones. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend reading more about these recipes
Silk Ice Cream 1/2 cup granulated sugar 1/4 tsp xantham gum 2 tbsp light corn syrup 1 1/3 cups + 1 tbsp of Silk Heavy Whipping Cream Alternative 1 cup - 1 tbsp of Oat Milk (you can substitute other milks, but do your math to recalculate the fat, see notes below) Combine sugar and xantham gum Put corn syrup in medium pot and stir in oat milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blanket Ladder</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/blanket-ladder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 20:42:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/blanket-ladder/</guid>
      <description>A custom ladder that stores blankets for our family room</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Passwordless User Authorization</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/passwordless-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 10:48:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/passwordless-auth/</guid>
      <description>I hate passwords. Not as a user as password management is basically solved with most modern browsers and password managers. What I hate is having to deal with them as a developer. Hashing, storing, authentication, etc.
I did a small project recently using my socket.io synced vuex state and needed a system where users could easily login. I will put a huge disclaimer on this that this is just what I did for my personal project where security isn&amp;rsquo;t critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vuex Sync Part 1</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vuex-sync-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 09:12:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vuex-sync-p1/</guid>
      <description>This is the tale of how I wrote a state syncing framework based on vuex and rollback netcode . It took a few years and isn&amp;rsquo;t intended to be a &amp;ldquo;copy and paste&amp;rdquo; type of thing. I&amp;rsquo;ll be including code fragments and I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually post a cleaned up repo with only the relevant pieces. Who knows, if there&amp;rsquo;s enough interest, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll even post a NPM package.
TL;DR This is a long article.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
