<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew C Dev</title>
    <link>https://matthewc.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matthew C Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 11:25:27 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matthewc.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making an Automated Livestreamed Gaming Platform</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/crowdtrivia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 11:25:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/crowdtrivia/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned Padgames here on the blog before, but there&amp;rsquo;s a common theme of creating games that everyone can gather around a central screen and play. Jackbox games are a staple in my house for that reason. I also was in college when Twitch Plays Pokemon reached its zennith. Over the past few months a friend of mine and I had been talking about creating automated Youtube channels. All these ideas sort of landed in my head and while isolating at home with a fever, these ideas seemed to merge in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding The Best Homemade Vegan Ice Cream</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vegan-ice-cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 13:15:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vegan-ice-cream/</guid>
      <description>Since I hate sites that make you read a whole story to get the recipes, out of the five different ice creams, here were the two highest ranking ones. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend reading more about these recipes
Silk Ice Cream 1/2 cup granulated sugar 1/4 tsp xantham gum 2 tbsp light corn syrup 1 1/3 cups + 1 tbsp of Silk Heavy Whipping Cream Alternative 1 cup - 1 tbsp of Oat Milk (you can substitute other milks, but do your math to recalculate the fat, see notes below) Combine sugar and xantham gum Put corn syrup in medium pot and stir in oat milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selectivity Rich</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/selective-rich/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 22:32:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/selective-rich/</guid>
      <description>I have a friend who claims food delivery is too expensive and would just go and pick it up themselves. To me, if I&amp;rsquo;m hot and tired from working on some house thing, I love just hitting a button and hopping in the shower knowing some kind soul will deliver food to my door by the time I&amp;rsquo;m out. Ethical concerns about food delivery companies aside (I try to tip well), it&amp;rsquo;s something I value more than my friend does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blanket Ladder</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/blanket-ladder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 20:42:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/blanket-ladder/</guid>
      <description>A custom ladder that stores blankets for our family room</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Ode To Paper Todos</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/paper-todos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 14:19:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/paper-todos/</guid>
      <description>I love a todo list. It captures my goals and desires in a semi-succinct and concrete way. There are hundreds if not thousands of todo apps and methods. But to me personally, one stands out above all the others.
A simple 3x5 notecard.
This is a how-to or a help article. This is a love letter.
A love letter to paper.
The simple idea of writing down your list of things to do on a physical surface with your own hand is something I love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burger Boy</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/blender/burger-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 09:48:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/blender/burger-boy/</guid>
      <description>I came across this little GIF of someone carving a little burger boy on imgur . As far as I can&amp;rsquo;t, the poster of this GIF isn&amp;rsquo;t the original carver. Doing a quick google doesn&amp;rsquo;t show any burger boys that are similar to this. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;m not stealing some beloved character. It&amp;rsquo;s just a thing I thought was cool.
Reference:
First Attempt The lighting is way too much and I need to add some texture onto the patty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Hybrid Future</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/plugin-hybrid-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 09:08:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/plugin-hybrid-future/</guid>
      <description>You might have heard the future of cars are electric. Here&amp;rsquo;s a shortlist from mashable that includes all the car manufacturers going electric only.
Bentley - 2030 Jaguar - 2030 GM - 2035 Volvo - 2030 Ford - 2026 (EU only) Volkswagen - 2026 Toyota - 2040 Mercedes - 2035 This list means they are pledging to no longer produce cars that have combustion engines. Many other auto manufacturers are pledging to sell mostly electric vehicles and sell a small number traditional gas cars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Passwordless User Authorization</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/passwordless-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 10:48:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/passwordless-auth/</guid>
      <description>I hate passwords. Not as a user as password management is basically solved with most modern browsers and password managers. What I hate is having to deal with them as a developer. Hashing, storing, authentication, etc.
I did a small project recently using my socket.io synced vuex state and needed a system where users could easily login. I will put a huge disclaimer on this that this is just what I did for my personal project where security isn&amp;rsquo;t critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vuex Sync Part 1</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vuex-sync-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 09:12:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vuex-sync-p1/</guid>
      <description>This is the tale of how I wrote a state syncing framework based on vuex and rollback netcode . It took a few years and isn&amp;rsquo;t intended to be a &amp;ldquo;copy and paste&amp;rdquo; type of thing. I&amp;rsquo;ll be including code fragments and I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually post a cleaned up repo with only the relevant pieces. Who knows, if there&amp;rsquo;s enough interest, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll even post a NPM package.
TL;DR This is a long article.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Great British Effect</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/great-british-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 20:42:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/great-british-effect/</guid>
      <description>You might remember the craze that was Great British Bakeoff in its heyday. There was discussion around the water cooler at work about each episode, parodies at SNL, and several spinoff series. While I personally feel that the hype has died down somewhat over the years as it&amp;rsquo;s been going for over 10 years.
While watching the most recent season, I noticed something interesting. There were three finalists and they were all incredible bakers in their own right.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my blog</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:38:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to start posting project logs here. The focus here will be:
Programming/Web dev Woodworking Game development Occasionally embedded/firmware type stuff Blender Maybe even baking? It&amp;rsquo;s hard to say exactly what will be here. I&amp;rsquo;ve brought over the medium articles I&amp;rsquo;ve written. I&amp;rsquo;ve included a link to the things I&amp;rsquo;ve written on Hackaday, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll bring the actual content over here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PC Penguins</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/blender/penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 16:14:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/blender/penguins/</guid>
      <description>This is an early attempt at blender from 2021. It started with a drawing that I loved. I&amp;rsquo;ve poked around Google Images but so far I haven&amp;rsquo;t found the original artist.
I quickly modeled a few things, trying to create a more 3d look rather than sticking with the more stylized look.
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this was ultimately the right choice. The moon was a little tricky to get right and I haven&amp;rsquo;t nailed the look of low light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nintendo 64: Architecture and History</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/nintendo-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:24:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/nintendo-64/</guid>
      <description>Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note: This was originally published on medium It stands as a unique and marvelous console even by today’s standards. Both from an technical as well as cultural standpoint, it was simply stupendous. This article showcases the history of the Nintendo 64 as well as explores it from a technical standpoint. If you’re like me, you likely have fond memories of this console. If you’re interested in the technical bits, skip ahead to the architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads? Where we’re going, we won’t have any roads.</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/no-roads-for-old-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 09:20:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/no-roads-for-old-men/</guid>
      <description>Editors Note: Originally posted on medium by me
At least, the way things are going here in the USA. Our roads, as we currently handle them, are unsustainable. As city and states are financially stretched in different and difficult ways, the incredible cost of road maintenance and construction is getting harder and harder for policy makers and government workers to manage. At the rate we are going there will be significantly fewer roads, more traffic, higher taxes, and more pot holes than either you or I could imagine in our worse nightmares.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
