<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew C Dev</title>
    <link>https://matthewc.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matthew C Dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 09:08:56 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matthewc.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plugin Hybrid Future</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/plugin-hybrid-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 09:08:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/plugin-hybrid-future/</guid>
      <description>You might have heard the future of cars are electric. Here&amp;rsquo;s a shortlist from mashable that includes all the car manufacturers going electric only.
 Bentley - 2030 Jaguar - 2030 GM - 2035 Volvo - 2030 Ford - 2026 (EU only) Volkswagen - 2026 Toyota - 2040 Mercedes - 2035  This list means they are pledging to no longer produce cars that have combustion engines. Many other auto manufacturers are pledging to sell mostly electric vehicles and sell a small number traditional gas cars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great British Effect</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/great-british-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 20:42:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/great-british-effect/</guid>
      <description>You might remember the craze that was Great British Bakeoff in its heyday. There was discussion around the water cooler at work about each episode, parodies at SNL, and several spinoff series. While I personally feel that the hype has died down somewhat over the years as it&amp;rsquo;s been going for over 10 years.
While watching the most recent season, I noticed something interesting. There were three finalists and they were all incredible bakers in their own right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Passwordless User Authorization</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/passwordless-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 20:56:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/passwordless-auth/</guid>
      <description>I hate passwords. Not as a user as password management is basically solved with most modern browsers and password managers. What I hate is having to deal with them as a developer. Hashing, storing, authentication, etc.
I did a small project recently using my socket.io synced vuex state and needed a system where users could easily login. I will put a huge disclaimer on this that this is just what I did for my personal project where security isn&amp;rsquo;t critical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vuex Sync Part 1</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vuex-sync-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 20:56:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/projects/vuex-sync-p1/</guid>
      <description>This is the tale of how I wrote a state syncing framework based on vuex and rollback netcode . It took a few years and isn&amp;rsquo;t intended to be a &amp;ldquo;copy and paste&amp;rdquo; type of thing. I&amp;rsquo;ll be including code fragments and I&amp;rsquo;ll eventually post a cleaned up repo with only the relevant pieces. Who knows, if there&amp;rsquo;s enough interest, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll even post a NPM package.
TL;DR This is a long article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my blog</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 20:38:57 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to start posting project logs here. The focus here will be:
 Programming/Web dev Woodworking Game development Occasionally embedded/firmware type stuff Maybe even baking?  It&amp;rsquo;s hard to say exactly what will be here. Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting links to any articles I write for Hackaday and Medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nintendo 64: Architecture and History</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/nintendo-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 10:24:36 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/nintendo-64/</guid>
      <description>Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note: This was originally published on medium 
It stands as a unique and marvelous console even by today’s standards. Both from an technical as well as cultural standpoint, it was simply stupendous. This article showcases the history of the Nintendo 64 as well as explores it from a technical standpoint. If you’re like me, you likely have fond memories of this console. If you’re interested in the technical bits, skip ahead to the architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roads? Where we’re going, we won’t have any roads.</title>
      <link>https://matthewc.dev/musings/no-roads-for-old-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 09:20:49 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matthewc.dev/musings/no-roads-for-old-men/</guid>
      <description>Editors Note: Originally posted on medium by me
At least, the way things are going here in the USA. Our roads, as we currently handle them, are unsustainable. As city and states are financially stretched in different and difficult ways, the incredible cost of road maintenance and construction is getting harder and harder for policy makers and government workers to manage. At the rate we are going there will be significantly fewer roads, more traffic, higher taxes, and more pot holes than either you or I could imagine in our worse nightmares.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
